rangde.org 2017-03-27

# Rang De - Privacy Policy

> Last revised on : Dec 29, 2016

Rang De is committed to maintaining the confidentiality, integrity and security of any personal information about our users. This Privacy & Security Policy explains how we protect personal information provided through our website www.rangde.org (the "Site") and how we use that information in connection with our service offered through the Site (the "Service"). "Personal information" for purposes of this Policy means information that identifies you, such as your name, address, phone number, fax number or email address.

Rang De stresses its privacy and security standards to guard against identity theft and provide security for your personal information. We regularly re-evaluate our privacy and security policies and adapt them as necessary to deal with new challenges.

* * *

#### We may use personal information to provide the services you've requested.

Simply put, we do not and will not sell or rent your personal information to anyone, for any reason, at any time. Rang De uses and discloses your personal information only as follows:

  * To analyze site usage and improve the service;
  * To deliver to you any administrative notices, notifications regarding your disbursements, social investments and repayments;
  * To fulfill your requests for certain services;
  * Or market research, project planning, troubleshooting problems, detecting and protecting against error, fraud or other criminal activity;
  * To third-party contractors that provide services to Rang De and are bound by these same privacy restrictions;
  * To third-party contractors that provide services to Rang De and are bound by these same privacy restrictions;
  * To enforce Rang De's Terms of Use; and
  * As otherwise set forth in this Privacy and Security Policy.

In the event that you access the Service as brought to you by one of our co-brand partners, through a co-branded URL, your email address used for registration on the Service may be provided to that co-brand partner.

* * *

#### We limit the collection and use of personal information.

Certain areas and features of RangDe.Org are available to you without registration or the need to provide to us any information. However, other features of the Site or the Service may require registration, which involves provision to Rang De of an email address, a password and your pin code and to participate on our forum boards, a username (collectively the 'Registration Information'). 

From time to time we may request other personal information to provide you with other benefits of the Service. In all such instances, you will be given the opportunity to provide or to decline to provide that information, and it will be used only for the stated purpose. Rang De may make anonymous or aggregate personal information and disclose such data only in a non-personally identifiable manner to: Advertisers and other third parties for their marketing and promotional purposes, such as the number of users and how many users clicked on a particular Rang De Offer; Organizations approved by Rang De that conduct research on philanthropy and social investing. Such information does not identify you individually. Access to your Registration Information, Account Credentials, Account Information and any other personal information you provide is strictly restricted and used in accordance with specific internal procedures and safeguard governing access, in order to operate, develop or improve the Service. These individuals have been selected in accordance with our security policies and practices and are bound by confidentiality obligations. They may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. We may also use third party vendors or service providers to help us provide the Service to you, such as sending e-mail messages on our behalf or hosting and operating a particular feature or functionality of the Service. Our contracts with these third parties outline the appropriate use and handling of your information and prohibit them from using any of your personal information for purposes unrelated to the product or service they're providing. We require such third parties to maintain the confidentiality of the information we provide to them.

* * *

#### Changes to your Registration Information.

If your Registration Information changes during your usage of Rang De, you may update it any time via the Service.

* * *

#### Online session information and use is only used to improve your experience

When you visit RangDe.Org, we may collect technical and navigational information, such as computer browser type, Internet protocol address, pages visited, and average time spent on our Site. This information may be used, for example, to alert you to software compatibility issues, or it may be analyzed to improve our Web design and functionality. 

"Cookies" are alphanumeric identifiers in the form of text files that are inserted and stored by your Web browser on your computer's hard drive. Rang De may set and access cookies on your computer to track and store preferential information about you. Rang De may gather information about you through cookie technology. For example, Rang De may assign a cookie to you, to limit the amount of times you see a particular Rang De Offer or to help better determine which Rang De Offers to serve to you. Please note that most Internet browsers will allow you to stop cookies from being stored on your computer and to delete cookies stored on your computer. If you choose to eliminate cookies, the full functionality of the Service may be impaired for you. 

We encode our cookies so that only we can interpret the information stored in them. 

Web beacons are images embedded in a Web page or email for the purpose of measuring and analyzing site usage and activity. Rang De, or third party service providers acting on our behalf, may use Web beacons to help us analyze Site usage and improve the Service. 

We may use third party service providers to help us analyze certain online activities. For example, these service providers may help us measure the performance of our online campaigns or analyze visitor activity on RangDe.Org. We may permit these service providers to use cookies and other technologies to perform these services for Rang De. We do not share any personal information about our customers with these third party service providers, and these service providers do not collect such information on our behalf. Our third party service providers are required to comply fully with this Privacy and Security Policy.

* * *

#### Blogs and other Forums on RangDe.Org

If you use a bulletin board, blog or chat room on our site, you should be aware that any information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. These forums may be hosted by Rang De or by one of our third party service providers on Rang De's behalf.

* * *

#### Contests, Giveaways and Surveys

From time to time, Rang De may offer you the opportunity to participate in contests, giveaways and other promotions. Any information submitted in connection with such activities will be treated in accordance with this Privacy and Security Policy, except as specifically set forth in the rules for those contests, giveaways or promotions. From time to time, Rang De may also ask you to participate in surveys designed to help Rang De improve the Site. Any personal information provided to Rang De in connection with any survey will be used only in relation to that survey and as elsewhere set forth in this Policy.

* * *

#### Disclosure of your information to protect our rights or if required by law

Notwithstanding the foregoing, Rang De reserves the right (and you authorize Rang De) to share or disclose your personal information when Rang De determines, in its sole discretion, that the disclosure of such information is necessary or appropriate:   
To enforce our rights against you or in connection with a breach by you of this Privacy and Security Policy or the RangDe.Org Terms of Use; To prevent prohibited or illegal activities; or When required by any applicable law, rule regulation, subpoena or other legal process.   

* * *

#### Your data may be transferred upon change of control but only in accordance with this Policy

Personal information may be transferred to a third party as a result of a sale, acquisition, merger, reorganization or other change of control. If we sell, merge or transfer any part of our business, part of the sale may include your personal information. If so, you will be asked if you'd like to stop receiving promotional information following any change of control.

* * *

#### You can transport or delete your data

Your data is yours. You can remove it anytime you want. When you request us to delete your account for the Service, your data will be permanently expunged from our primary production servers and further access to your account will not be possible. We will also promptly disconnect any connection we had established to your Account Information and delete all account credentials. However, portions of your data, consisting of aggregate data derived from your Account Information, may remain on our production servers indefinitely. Your data may also remain on a backup server or media. Rang De keeps these backups to ensure our continued ability to provide the Service to you in the event of malfunction or damage to our primary production servers. We also reserve the right to use any aggregated or anonymous data derived from or incorporating your personal information.

* * *

#### Email communications from us

We provide our registered customers with monthly summaries of their social investments. We also allow users to subscribe to email newsletters and from time to time may transmit emails promoting Rang De. RangDe.Org subscribers have the ability to opt-out of receiving our promotional emails, terminate their newsletter subscriptions but they will still receive information regarding completed transactions, monthly investment reminders that they have subscribed to and any urgent updates based on technical changes or exigent circumstances (natural disasters, policy changes etc). 

* * *

#### You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your Login ID and Password

We maintain rules to help prevent others from guessing your password. We also recommend that you change your password periodically. Your password must be 6-8 characters in length. You are responsible for maintaining the security of your Login ID and Password. You may not provide these credentials to any third party. If you believe that they have been stolen or been made known to others, you must contact us immediately at security@RangDe.Org, but in any event you should change your password immediately via the Service. We are not responsible if someone else accesses your account through Registration Information they have obtained from you or through a violation by you of this Privacy and Security Policy or the RangDe.Org Terms of Use. 

If you have a security related concern, please contact us at security@RangDe.Org. We will work closely with you to ensure a rapid and personal response to your concerns. 

* * *

#### We post updates on our website whenever there is a change to our Privacy and Security Policy

We update this Privacy & Security Policy periodically. The date last revised appears at the top of the Policy. Changes take effect immediately upon posting.

* * *

#### Contact us if you have any questions or concerns

If you have questions, comments, concerns or feedback regarding this Privacy and Security Policy or any other privacy or security concern, send an e-mail to security@RangDe.Org.
